好  这些非常昂贵  而且我知道他很快就穿不下…
Okay, these were expensive, and he's gonna grow out of them...
但我就是无法抗拒
...in 20 minutes, but I couldn't resist!
看看这些鞋子
Look at these.
嘿  小班
Hey, Ben.
穿就对了
"Just do it"! Unh!
噢  天哪
Oh, my God! Oh!
那样对他是不是压力太大
Was that too much pressure for him?
他又饿了吗  我想是
Oh, is he hungry already? Aw. I guess so.
你知道…
You know, it's...
球鞋真的很有趣  我马上回来
Something funny about sneakers. I'll be right back.
喔… 我也是
Oh, uh, I gotta get one too.
嘿  你们在干嘛
Hey, what are you guys doing?
我们只是在玩汤匙
We're just hanging out by the spoons.
调羹
Ladle?
你们可不可以成熟一点
Will you guys grow up?
这是全天下最自然最美好的事物
This is the most natural, beautiful thing in the world.
我们知道  但有个婴儿在吸吮它
Yeah, we know. But there's a baby sucking on it.
我儿子在吃午餐  这会常常发生  最好赶快习惯
This is my son having lunch, okay? It'll happen a lot, so get used to it.
如果你有问题或不自在  问问题就行了
If you have a problem, if you're uncomfortable, just ask questions.
卡萝没问题的  快点
Carol's fine with it. Come on.
卡萝   卡萝
Carol?  Carol.
我想知道乔伊可不可以问你一个喂母乳的问题
I was wondering if Joey could ask you a question about breast-feeding?
当然可以   啊
Sure.  Uh...
会痛吗
Does it hurt?
一开始会  不过再也不会了
It did at first, but not anymore.
钱德
Chandler?
你可以多久喂一次
So, uh, how often can you do it?
只要他有需要都行
As much as he needs.
好  我有了…
Oh, okay, I got one, I got one. Uh...
如果他对一个吹气  另一个会不会变大
If he blows into one, does the other one get bigger?
《老友记》  第二季  第2集  喂母乳
Friends S02E02: The One With the Breast Milk
（主演：詹妮弗·安妮斯顿）
（主演：柯特妮·考克斯）
（主演：丽莎·库卓）
（主演：马特·勒布朗）
（主演：马修·派瑞）
（主演：大卫·修蒙）
瑞秋  你们还有松饼吗  还有 不过我忘记是哪一种了
Rachel, do you have muffins left? Yeah, I forget which ones.
你在忙  我自己去拿
Oh, you're busy, I'll get it.
还有其他人要吗   不用了 谢谢
Anyone else want one? No, thanks.
我不用
No, I'm all set.
你的围裙快掉了  我帮你
Oh, you're losing your apron. Let me get it.
噢   好了
Oh. There you go.
谢谢
Thank you.
自以为是的贱人
Ugh, what a bitch.
（制片：塔德·史帝文斯）
各位  我有个朋友在布鲁明戴尔百货上班  明天就不干了
Listen, guys, I have a friend at Bloomingdale's who's quitting...
（制片：贝西·伯恩斯）
他想要花掉他的折扣券
...and he wants to abuse his discount.
谁要跟我去捡便宜
So anyone want to come take advantage of it?
我没办法  我得带我祖母去看兽医
I can't. I have to take my grandmother to the vet.
好  我跟你去  太好了
Okay. Um, I'll go with you. Great.
（编剧：亚当·却斯 艾拉·安德里德）
嗨  亲爱的  嘿  甜心
Hi, honey.  Hey, sweetums.
哈罗   各位  嗨
And hello to the rest. Hi.
摩妮卡  你在干嘛
What are you doing?
你不能跟她去购物  那瑞秋怎么办
You can't go shopping with her. What about Rachel?
（导演：麦可·连贝克）
会有问题 对吧   拜托
It's gonna be a problem, isn't it? Come on.
你要跟茱莉去布鲁明戴尔
You're going to Bloomingdale's with Julie.
这就像到瑞秋家中偷汉子
It's like cheating on Rachel in her house of worship.
但是我…  摩妮卡  她会宰了你
But I... Monica, she will kill you.
她会宰了你  像宰流浪狗一样
She will kill you like a dog in the street!
茱莉跟我说你们明天要一起去购物
So, uh, Jules tells me you guys are going shopping tomorrow.
其实没什么大不了的  其实…
Yeah, um, it's actually not that big a deal. In fact...
这对我很重要  太棒了  我真的很感激
It's a big deal to me. This is great. I really appreciate this.
不客气
You're welcome.
毕坚男性香水
Bijan for men?
嘿  安娜贝尔   嘿  乔伊
Hey, Annabel. Hey, Joey.
你有听过那个新家伙的事吗   谁
Did you hear about the new guy? Who?
没有人知道他的名字  我们女生都叫他〝原野奇侠〞
Nobody knows his name. Me and the girls call him "The Hombre Man."
原野奇侠
Hombre?
他在我这一区干嘛
What's he doing in my section?
我猜他不知道吧
I guess he doesn't know.
他很快就会知道了
Well, he's gonna.
待会见  好吗
I'll see you a little later, okay?
你好吗
Hey, how you doing?
早安
Morning.
我知道你是新来的…
Listen, uh, heh. I know you're new...
但众所皆知  这附近的一切…
...but, uh, it's kind of understood that everything...
从年轻人部门到电梯… 都是我的地盘
...from young men's to the escalator is, uh, my territory.
你的地盘   对
Your territory, huh? Yeah.
毕坚男性香水  不用  谢谢
Bijan for men? No, thanks.
原野奇侠
Hombre?
好啊
Yeah, all right.
你刚刚说什么
You were saying?
菲比  听好  你今天和我在一起一整天都一起购物
Phoebe, listen. You were with me, and we were shopping all day.
什么  我们一起购物然后吃午餐
What? We were shopping and we had lunch.
好  我吃了什么
All right. What did I have?
你吃沙拉   难怪我还觉得饿
You had a salad. No wonder I don't feel full.
嘿  你们好吗
Hi, guys. What's up?
我和摩妮卡去购物  我吃了沙拉
I went shopping with Monica all day and I had a salad.
很好  菲比  你买了什么
Good, Pheebs. What'd you buy?
我们买了…
We went shopping for, um...
买了…
For, um...
皮草
For fur.
你去买皮草    对
You went shopping for fur? Yeah.
然后我发现我反对买皮草
And then I realized that I'm against that and, um...
所以我们买了一些…
So then we bought some, um...
胸部
Um, boobs.
你买了胸部
You bought boobs?
胸罩啦
Bras!
我们买了胸罩
We bought bras!
We bought bras.
毕坚男性香水
Bijan for men?
毕坚男性…
Bijan for...
嘿   安娜贝尔
Hey, Annabel. Uh...
我在想  你下班后要不要一起喝杯咖啡
Listen, I was wondering if after work we could grab a cup of coffee?
我已经有计划了
Actually, I sort of have plans.
准备好了吗  安娜贝尔
You ready, Annabel?
好了
You bet.
或许下次吧   好
Maybe some other time. Yeah.
这不是我第一次被喷香水的牛仔抢走女孩子了
It's not the first time I lost a girl to a cowboy spraying cologne.
毕坚男性香水
Bijan for men?
Bijan for men!
好  这是滑稽小丑
Okay, and this is Funny Clown.
滑稽小丑只能在午睡后玩  否则他会睡不着
Funny Clown is only for after his naps, not before or he won't sleep.
卡萝  我们已经谈过这件事了  我们玩得很开心
We've been through this before. We have a good time.
我们又笑又玩  就像父亲跟儿子一样
We laugh, we play. It's like we're father and son.
亲爱的  别担心  罗斯很会照顾他
Honey, relax. Ross is great with him.
别这么惊讶  我是个和善的人
Don't look so surprised. I'm a lovely person.
噢  这好可爱
Oh, this is so cute.
我帮他买的
Ah, I got that for him!
〝我的妈妈们爱我〞
"My Mommies Love Me."
真聪明
That's clever.
喂
Hello?
噢  嗨  茱…
Oh, hi, Jul...
嗨  朱
Hi, Jew!
好啊  当然
Uh-huh. Okay, um, sure.
太好了  到时候见  拜
That'd be great. See you then. Bye.
你刚刚说〝嗨  朱〞吗
Did you just say, "Hi, Jew"?
对  没错
Yes. Um, yes, I did.
刚刚是我的〝猪〞朋狗友打来的
That was my friend Eddie Moskowitz.
他喜欢我这样叫他  好笑嘛
Yeah, he likes it. Reaffirms his faith.
班  吃晚餐了
Ben, dinner!
谢了  菲比阿姨
Thanks, Aunt Pheebs.
你不是用微波的吧  母奶不可以用微波的
You didn't microwave that, did you? It's breast milk, you're not supposed to.
我知道怎么加热母奶
Duh, I think I know how to heat breast milk. Heh.
好
Okay.
你刚刚做了什么
What did you just do?
我舔了手臂啊  干嘛
I licked my arm, what?
是母奶耶
It's breast milk!
那又怎样
So?
菲比  那是人身上挤出来的奶
Phoebe, that is juice squeezed from a person.
那又怎样   不…
What is the big deal? No, no...
你做了什么好事
What did you just do?
你们可以不要再喝母奶了吗
Can people stop drinking the breast milk?
你连尝尝看都不肯  不要
You won't even taste it? - No.
连假装它是牛奶都不行吗
Not even if you just pretend it's milk?
就算卡萝的乳房贴了寻人启事都不行
Not even if Carol's breast had a picture of a missing child on it.
嘿   嗨
Hey. Hi.
大家都去哪了  带小班去公园玩
Where is everybody?  Took Ben to the park.
你去哪了   出去一下
Where have you been?  Just out.
吃了午餐  只有我一个人与自己共度的美好时光
Had some lunch. Just me. A little quality time with me.
谢谢你的外套  噢  没问题
Hey, thanks for your jacket. Oh, no problem.
你也可以向我借
You can borrow it, by the way. Heh.
你的钥匙在这里   谢谢
Oh, here are your keys, honey. Thank you.
摩妮卡
Mon? Mm-hmm?
如果你是一个人吃午餐  怎么会花了五十三块
If, uh, you were at lunch alone, how come it cost you $53?
你知道发生什么事吗
You know what probably happened?
大概有人偷了我的信用卡
Someone must have stolen my credit card. Ah.
然后把帐单放回你的口袋
And put the receipt back in your pocket?
这是个很棒的问题  很棒
Huh. That is an excellent, excellent question.
太棒了
That is excellent.
你怎么了  你跟谁一起吃午餐
What's with you? Who did you have lunch with?
茱蒂  谁
Judy. Who?
茱莉 乔蒂   什么
Julie. Jody? What?
你跟茱莉出去  听着
You were with Julie? Mm. Look.
一开始  我只是想对她好一点…
When it started, I was just trying to be nice to her...
因为她是我哥的女朋友
...because she was my brother's girlfriend.
然后事情接着发生…
And then one thing led to another...
在我搞清楚之前… 我们就…
...and before I knew it, we were...
一起购物了
...shopping. Aah.
天啊
Oh, my God.
等等  我们只做了一次
Wait, we only did it once.
对我一点意义也没有
It didn't mean anything to me.
是啊  是真的
Yeah, right. Sure. Really!
瑞秋  我心里想的都是你
Rachel, I was thinking of you the whole time.
听着  我真的很抱歉  好吗  我从来都不想让你发现
Look, I'm sorry, all right? I never meant for you to find out.
拜托  你很想被逮到
Oh, please! Please! You wanted to get caught!
乱讲
That is not true!
所以你是不小心把收据留在这里
So you just happened to leave it in here?
你有没有想过我或许就是那么笨
Did it ever occur to you that I might just be that stupid?
好  摩妮卡  我需要知道一件事
Okay, Monica, I just have to know one thing.
你有跟她一起去布鲁明戴尔吗
Did you go with her to Bloomingdale's?
好…
Okay. Okay.
好  我只是  我现在无法跟你在一起
Okay, I just really, um... I just need to not be with you right now.
喂  哪一位
Hi, who's this?
嗨  乔安  瑞秋有上班吗  我是摩妮卡
Hi, Joanne. Is Rachel working? It's Monica.
我知道我做了很糟糕的事
Yes, I know I did a horrible thing.
乔安  事情不是那么简单
Joanne, it's not as simple as all that, okay?
不  我不在乎史提夫怎么想的  嗨  史提夫
No, I don't care what Steve thinks. Hi, Steve.
嘿   嗨！
Hey! Hi!
做得怎样啊
How did we do?
我尝了小班的母奶  罗斯吓坏了
Oh, I tasted Ben's milk and Ross freaked out.
我没有吓坏
I... I did not freak out.
为什么你会吓坏   因为那是母奶
Why'd you freak out?  Because it's breast milk.
超恶心的
It's gross!
我的母奶很恶心
My breast milk is gross?
有趣了
This should be fun.
不是  卡萝  你的母奶没有问题
No, Carol. There's nothing wrong with it.
我只是觉得母奶不是成人喝的
I just don't think breast milk is for adults.
当然  母奶的包装大人小孩都喜欢
Of course, the packaging does appeal to grownups and kids.
罗斯  别傻了  我试过了  这没什么
Ross, you're being silly. I've tried it. It's no big deal.
来嘛  尝一点
Come on, just taste it.Ha-ha-ha.
我不要
That would be no.
别这样  试试看
Come on. Try it.
是天然的  味道不错啊
It's natural.  It doesn't taste bad.
喝起来甜甜的 有点像…
Yeah, it tastes kind of sweet. Sort of like, uh...
像什么   哈蜜瓜汁
Like what?  Cantaloupe juice.
没错
Exactly.
你有喝过
You've tasted it.
噢  你有喝过
Oh, you've tasted it.
你可以一直说  但这句话也不会变成假的
You can keep saying it, but it won't stop being true.
瓶子给我
Give me the bottle.
毛巾给我
Get me the towel.
你好啊
Howdy.
给我一瓶果汁
Give me a box ofjuice.
他们把我换到原野奇侠
Well, they switched me over to Hombre.
或许是因为你的打扮
Maybe it's because of the way you're dressed.
又或许是因为这家伙很厉害  他们要增加人手
Or maybe this guy's doing so good they want to put more people on it.
你该看看这家伙  他现在一天可以用掉两瓶
This guy goes through two bottles a day now.
你在乎什么
What do you care?
你是演员  这只是你的副业  没什么大不了
You're an actor. This is your day job. Isn't supposed to mean anything.
我知道  但我以前是最棒的
I know, but I was the best.
我喜欢当最厉害的那个人
You know? I liked being the best.
不知道  或许我该退出了
Maybe I should get out of the game.
厨具部门需要有人切乳酪
They need guys up in housewares to serve cheese.
假如你这么做了
Say you do that.
迟早有人乳酪会切得比你好
Sooner or later, somebody will come along that slices a better cheddar.
到时候你要逃到哪里去
And then where you gonna run?
你说得没错  我当然是对的
I guess you're right.  Damn right I'm right.
你让这家伙看看你的能耐  捍卫你的领土
Show this guy what you're made of. Stand your ground.
让他知道你是内衣部西边最厉害的原野奇侠
Show him that you're the baddest Hombre west of the lingerie!
我这就去  好！
I'm gonna do it!  All right!
现在去找猫咪小姐  她会介绍个好妓女给你
Now, go see Miss Kitty and she'll fix you up with a nice hooker.
我不知道还能说什么
MONICA: I don't know what to say.
很好  因为我根本没在听
That works good because I'm not listening.
我觉得糟透了  真的
I feel terrible. I really do.
噢  抱歉  我的背伤到你的刀吗
Oh, I'm sorry. Did my back hurt your knife?
瑞秋
Rachel!
我跟她交朋友  一起去逛街
Say that I'm friends with her. We spend time together.
有那么糟吗   对
Is that so terrible?  Yes.
有那么糟   是的 摩妮卡 你根本不懂
It's that terrible?  Yes, Monica! You don't get it.
她偷走我的男人已经够糟了
It's bad enough she stole the guy...
一个我可能会长相厮守的男人
...who may be the person I'm supposed to be with.
但是现在…
But now...
她竟然…
...she's actually...
她竟然连你也抢走了！
But now she's actually stealing you!
我
Me?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
没人能把我从你那里抢走
Nobody could steal me from you.
我跟她交朋友不会影响你跟我的感情
Because I'm friends with her doesn't make me any less friends with you.
亲爱的
Honey.
你是我…
I mean, you're my...
我们…
And we're...
噢  我爱你  我也爱你！
Oh, I love you!  I love you too!
两位  我知道这跟我一点关系都没有
You guys, um, I know that this really doesn't have anything to do with me.
但我也好爱你们
But, um, I love you guys too!
我真的很需要纸巾
Ugh, I really needed that.
我知道你现在的情况…
Look, I know you're in a place right now...
让你很讨厌茱莉
...where you really need to hate Julie's guts.
但是她并没有做错任何事
But she didn't do anything wrong.
她只是认识了一个男生  现在他们在交往
She's just a girl who met a guy, and now they go out.
如果你给她点机会  你也会喜欢她的
I think that if you gave her a chance, you'd like her.
你愿意给她一个机会吗
Will you give that a chance?
就为了我
For me?
我愿意为你做任何事  你知道的
I'd do anything for you, you know that.
我愿意为你做任何事
I'd do anything for you!
等等…
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
早安
Morning.
我说了  早安
Heh. I said, morning.
我听到了
I heard you.
好吧  各位  我要开门了
All right, everybody. I'm opening the doors.
你们准备好了吗
You boys ready?
好了
Ready.
我准备好了
Yeah, I'm ready.
你这白痴  白痴牛仔
You idiot! You stupid cowboy!
你害我看不到了  我要告你
You've blinded me! I'm suing!
天啊  陶德  你干了什么好事
Oh, my God! Todd! What the hell did you do?
对不起  我真是笨手笨脚
I'm sorry. I'm such a doofus!
我真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
天啊  发生什么事了
My God, what happened?
这些菜鸟都待不久
Eh, these new kids, they never last.
他们迟早都会…
Sooner or later they all...
不再久留
...stop lasting.
不如我现在就请你喝杯咖啡如何
Listen, uh, what do you say I buy you that cup of coffee now?
好啊
Sure.
那么… 那么…
So.  So.
我想说我们两个人应该多多亲近
I just thought the two of us should hang out a bit.
你知道  我们没有真的好好谈过
I mean, you know, we've never really talked.
我想你也知道 毕竟你也是当事人之一
I guess you'd know that, being one of the two of us. Ha, ha, right?
我知道
I know.  Mm.
我大概不该跟你讲这个…
I probably shouldn't even tell you this...
但是我还蛮怕你的
...but I'm pretty much totally intimidated by you.
真的吗  怕我
Really? Me?
天啊  开什么玩笑
Oh, my God, are you kidding?
罗斯超迷恋你的…
Ross is so crazy about you...
我真的很希望你能喜欢我  我又…
...and I really wanted you to like me, and I...
大概只是我自己乱想吧…
It's probably me just being totally paranoid...
我觉得你好像不想喜欢我
...but I kind of got the feeling that maybe you don't.
嗯…
Well...
你并不是在乱想
...you're not totally paranoid.
好
Okay. Um...
天啊
God. Um... - Heh.
你跟罗斯一开始交往的时候…
When you and, uh, Ross first started going out...
我真的很难过
...it was really hard for me, um...
有很多原因  细节就不多说了
...for many reasons of which I'm not gonna bore you with now, but, um...
我看到他很快乐  你们两个人很相配
I see how happy he is and how good you guys are together.
而且摩妮卡老是说你人很好…
And, um, Monica's always saying how nice you are...
我真讨厌她是对的
...and God, I hate it when she's right.
谢谢  嗯
Thanks.  Yeah.
嘿  你会想要偶尔一起去看点电影吗
Listen. Would you like to go to a movie sometime or something?
好啊  那会很棒   是吗
Yeah, that'd be great. I'd love it.  Yeah?
我也会喜欢   好
I'd love it too. Okay. Okay.
噢  我该走了  好
Oh, shoot, I gotta go.  Okay.
晚点再聊了  好  茱莉
So I'll talk to you later.  All right, Julie.
拜  拜
Bye.  Bye.
真是个会玩弄人的贱人
What a manipulative bitch.
还不赖嘛
It's not bad.